Isaac O. SANGODARE

Frontend Developer | JavaScript | React | TypeScript | Tailwind | Python | Django | Django | Restframework

Lagos, Nigeria | +2348068290320

CAREER SUMMARY

Experience: Over 2 years as a Freelancer and an Instructor, converting UI designs to frontend codes.

Languages: JavaScript, Python, Sql, Postgresql

Library: React, JQuery, Django, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Scss, Material UI Tools: Vscode, PostMan, Git, Github, Figma, Documentation

Communities: Teens Can Code, Stackover-flow, Google, frontendMentor, tech-twitter.

PROFFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelancer January 2021 - Present

Frontend Developer

Technologies: Javascript, React, CSS, Bootstrap, Google Suite, Git, GitHub, figma, HTML

- Worked with different Organizations and individuals, developing, Landing pages, E-commerce Websites, Portfolio Sites, Blogging Sites and others using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Reactjs.
- Part of 3-person team, working on redesigning of an institution website.
- Fixed bugs and issues in the any frontend part of clients' website.
- Built the frontend and connected the endpoints using Axios to the backend.

Lagos School of Programming

Full-stack Developer (Instructor)

December 2021 - Present

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, GitHub, Reactjs, Python, Django, sql, postgresql

- Provided academic assistance to assigned students individually and in groups
- Conducted practice tests to track progress, identify areas of improvement and help set goals for final assessment.
- Review classroom projects and homework, projects
- Part of 2-person team, working on redesigning of https://www.lasop.net/ frontend and connected some portion of the website to firebase

Projects

Ecommerce Website

https://bright-gumdrop.netlify.app/

Technologies: Reactjs, Tailwind CSS, useReducer, useContext, React Lazy

- A dynamic and intuitive platform, designed to deliver an exceptional shopping experience.
- Utilizing useReducer and useContext for optimized state management, axios for back-end communication, and react-router-dom for routing, the website offers a seamless navigation.
- The visually appealing interface, built with tailwind CSS and react-icons, enhances user engagement. Lazy loading optimizes page loading speed, ensuring a fast and smooth user experience.

Movie Search App

https://92isaac.github.io/Movie-app/

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Axios

- Built a dynamic platform that delivers an immersive viewing experience. Built using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Axios, the website integrates with the TMDB API to provide users with up-to-date information on the latest movies and TV shows.
- The use of Axios ensures efficient communication with the API, while Bootstrap provides a responsive design that adapts to different screen sizes.

• With its sleek and user-friendly interface, the website offers a smooth navigation and an engaging user experience. This project showcases our skills in web development and API integration, delivering a high-quality movies website that meets the demands of the modern user.

https://www.github.com/92isaac has more of the project I've had the honor of working on.

Educational and Work Experience

LAGOS SCHOOL OF PROGRAMMING

Fullstack Web Development Student

August 2021 - December 2021

Created multiple web application, worked in a team environment as well as individual to build frontend, backend and fullstack projects using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React for frontend and Django for backend.

Education

Ladoke Akintola University of Technology - Urban and Regional Planning
Chartered Institute of Project and Management - Project & Facility Management

^{**}References available upon request**